Brian Brenner

INTERN SOFTWARE ENGINEER / STUDENT

(440) 715-3009 ☐
brian.brenner.1@outlook.com
brianrbrenner in
brianrbrenner

EDUCATION

Computer Science, B.S.

Kent State University GPA: 3.9 2020-2023

Integrated Avionics A.A.S.

Air University 2016-2021

PROJECTS

Admin Portal Tech Lead

CHAMPTitles
Working as the lead
developer on an in-house
client administration tool.
2021 - Current

Combat Shield Team Lead

Verification and correction of Classified Surface-to-Air Missile software and hardware effectiveness. 2017 - 2019

AWARDS

Air Force Achievement Medal with Oak Leaf Cluster

309th Aircraft Maintenance Unit - 2017 / 2020

PROFILE

I am currently a full-stack Intern Software Engineer, Reservist in the Air Force as a Communication/Navigation Avionics Technician, and undergrad pursuing a Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science at Kent State University. I have over 4 years of hands-on experience working with software and hardware both in enterprise, and on aircraft. My pursuit is securing a part-time role in Software Development in order to extend my abilities while bringing value to the organization.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Intern Software Engineer - Hybrid

CHAMPTitles Inc. | August 2021 - Current

Extremely fast paced start up with consistently shifting business demands in modern technologies such as Java Spring Boot, React 17 + Redux, AWS ECS, AWS CloudWatch and mysql.

- Technical lead for front-end and back-end internal application team involving daily code reviews and pull requests.
- Greenfield development on React TS frontend with Keycloak Auth and REST API.

F-16 Integrated Avionics Technician

United States Air Force and Air Force Reserve | June 2016 - Current

- Analysis, installation, repair and maintenance of avionics systems to include: Communications, navigation aids, flight controls, radar systems, LITENING targeting pods, countermeasures, and display systems on 28 different F-16 aircraft, 9 different C-130 Aircraft.
- Responsible for loading and validating classified Operational Flight
 Program software and modification to enhance integrated computer
 capabilities.
- Monitored, interpreted, and analyzed data processed through automated systems for fault detection and reporting procedures.
- Isolated faults, interpreted system failures and blueprints through technical data and critical thinking.

SKILLS

TECHNICAL

- C++
- C
- React JS
- TypeScript
- Java
- Git
- Docker
- Spring
- Camunda

PROFESIONAL

- Team Building
- Active Listening
- Punctuality
- Interpersonal Skills
- Prioritization
- Brainstorming
- Problem Solving
- Logical Thought Process

PERSONAL PROJECTS

PLOX

A Lox language interpreter written in modern C++ featuring garbage collection and a recursive descent parser. The language features dynamic typing, classes, functions, control flow, primitives, and much more.

HR Management

A Human Resources portal application that features a REST API using PHP, CSS, HTML, JavaScript and MySQL.

REFERENCES

Cody Smith
CHAMPTitles Software Engineer III | Direct Supervisor (440) 336-0440

Christopher Gangloff F-16 Avionics Systems Craftsman | Direct Supervisor (760) 710-7402 christopher.gangloff.1@us.af.mil

Gary Kohut C-130 Avionics Systems Superintendent | Manager (330) 980-0902 gary.kohut.1@us.af.mil